you don't like
Secrets but when you get in on a secret
does it kind of make you feel like oh I
know about I know that
too well today we're going to be talking
about the secret of the Lord how many of
you would like to know that secret all
right there we go uh let's uh let's
begin with a word of prayer and I'm
going to make a special request because
I'm going to need your mind's like super
focused right now I know you've been
sitting for a little while so I'm going
to ask would you all just stand up for a
moment
yeah I need your minds to be in
full full action as we begin so all
right everyone is uh refreshed are you
happy are you excited all right we're
about to get into the word of God Amen
all right you may be
seated you may be seated Heavenly Father
we want to ask again that your presence
be with us guide us as we open your word
in Jesus name we pray amen proverbs
the 8th chapter Proverbs chapter
8 the
secrets Proverbs the 8th
chapter we're going to begin
reading from verse
14 Proverbs chapter 8 ver14 when you're
there let me hear you say
Amen prover prbs chapter
8 in fact let's begin with verse let's
begin with verse
22 now the context of Proverbs chapter 8
um is very simply in one word wisdom
wisdom is here being personified and as
we pick up in verse uh 22 we're going to
see what the Bible says about wisdom the
Bible says in verse 22 the Lord
possessed me so who would that me be
wisdom all right you got it so this is
wisdom speaking the Lord possessed me in
the beginning of his way before his
works of old I was set up from
Everlasting from the beginning orever
the Earth was when there were no depths
I was brought forth when there was no
fountains abounding with water before
the mountains were settled before the
hills was I was brought
forth while as yet he had not made the
Earth nor the fields nor the highest
part of the Dust of the world when he
prepared the heavens I was there when he
set a compass upon the face of the depth
when he established the clouds above
when he strengthened The Fountains of
the deep when he gave to the Sea his
decree that the waters should not pass
his commandment when he appointed the
foundation of the earth then I was by
him as one brought up with him and I was
daily his Delight rejoicing always
before him
who does it sound like speaking here
sounds like Jesus speaking amen uh it
it's as though the Book of Proverbs
chapter 8 is using wisdom as a symbol of
Christ and as we read these things about
Christ we know yes Christ was there with
the heavenly father uh at the creation
of the world and so we know that chapter
8 of Proverbs is talking about Christ
but this presents a dilemma you see
proverbs tells us that at some point
wisdom was brought
forth that's what it appears to be
saying a and if wisdom was was brought
forth at some
point then does this suggest that Jesus
was brought forth at some point in other
words did Jesus have a
beginning was Jesus at some point
brought forth and and I'm I'm mentioning
this because there are there are those
who look at Proverbs 8 and believe that
it is teaching that wisdom as Christ was
brought forth so was Proverbs 8 written
to tell us that Christ at some point Had
An Origin or is there a much deeper
meaning to Proverbs chapter 8 that's
what we're going to be talking about
today the secret so let's go over to the
Book of Matthew we're going to come back
to Proverbs 8 but I want to take you
over to the Book of Matthew chapter 13
we're going to begin with verse 34 by
the way in order to understand what is
being spoken about here in Proverbs
chapter 8 we need something what do you
think we
need wisdom thank you Joseph I'm glad
you were tuning in on that in order to
understand what Proverbs 8 is talking
about we need wisdom and James 1:5 tells
us if any of you lack wisdom let them
ask of God and God will do what give it
amen so that's what we want to ask for
Lord give us wisdom
as we seek to understand Proverbs
chapter 8 God is going to give us wisdom
I believe it because we have prayed it
now I want you to notice Matthew Chapter
13 Matthew Chapter
13 and verse
34 and
35 Matthew 13:34 all these things spake
Jesus unto the multitude in what
Parables and without a parable spake he
not un to them that it might be
fulfilled which was spoken by the
prophets
saying I will open my mouth in what
Parables I will utter things that have
been kept what secret from the
foundation of the world okay so what
does this tell us here a couple things
first of
all according to
Jesus were there things that were kept
secret from the foundation of the world
yes so if they were kept secret what
would that mean who would know about
it who who would know about
it right God and obviously who Jesus why
because Jesus is saying hey I'm going to
tell you things that have been kept
secret from the foundation of the world
so far so good all right so if only God
and Jesus knew what that mean about all
other creation from the foundation of
the
world did they know
no would it be safe to say that not even
angels would have known yeah have these
things are secret God knows them if
you're with me so far just say Amen all
right now check this out the word here
for Parable it's very
interesting
because the word literally
means
proverb all right this just be a me
alone excitement moment so I'm getting
excited the word means
proverb yeah you know what that tells
us a parable is a proverb or a proverb
is a par so when we look at Proverbs
chapter
8 what we are looking at is a what is a
parable amen and we understand that
parables are not meant to be taken how
literally there is a lesson behind the
parable and so that's why we need the
wisdom of God we need to understand what
is God trying to tell us here in
Proverbs chapter 8 by the way after
studying Proverbs chapter 8 I believe it
is one of the most precious chapters in
all of the Bible because it tells us
things that that you will not find in
any other single chapter in the
Bible let's let's let's figure this out
so we know one thing so far that there
were secrets from the foundation of the
world number one and number two that the
Proverbs are really Parables let's go
over to the Book of Romans chapter
16 and and here's what we want to do we
want to discover something by the way I
want to read something to you this is
going to be very interesting listen this
is actually from the book The Great
controversy and I want you to listen to
what it says on page 523 are you ready
for this it is a masterpiece of Satan's
deception to keep the minds of men
searching and conjecturing in regard to
that which God has not made known and
which he does not intend that we shall
understand it was thus that Lucifer lost
his place in heaven he became
dissatisfied because all the secrets of
God's purposes were not confided to
him what was not confided to
him okay so that God has some
secrets that Lucifer did not know
about that led him to wonder well why
can't I know yeah yeah all right so so
so so far we see that Jesus says hey I'm
going to tell you secret things things
that have been kept secret from the
foundation of the world we also
see that that according to the great
controversy Lucifer became jealous
because he could not find out or was not
privy to those
Secrets very interesting The Book of
Romans chapter 16 and and you can write
these verses down because I've got them
written down up here so I'm going to
kind of read through them pretty quickly
because I want to get to some major
points but Romans 16 verse 25 listen to
what it says now to
him that is of power to establish you
according to my gospel and the preaching
of Jesus Christ according to the
revelation of the mystery which was Kept
Secret since the world
began all right we're we're building
something here so I have a question for
you what is the secret since the world
began according to this verse what was
it
called the revelation of the what of the
what of the mystery which was Kept
Secret since the foundation of the world
so we can safely say that whatever this
secret was it the Bible calls it the
mystery all right a mystery is something
that is hard to what understand and in
order to understand it you would
probably need some
wisdom so far so good all right so this
mystery was kept since the foundation of
the world let me read another
translation to you the ASV version says
this now to him that is able to
establish you according to my gospel and
the preaching of Jesus Christ according
to the revelation of the mystery which
has been kept in silence through times
Eternal so it's not just saying that
this was a mystery from you know the
beginning of the Earth this was a
mystery from before the world was
created
amen all
right 1 Peter 1 Peter chapter n 1 Peter
chapter 1 1 Peter chapter
1 and uh notice with me verses
9 to 12 1 Peter
chapter
1 verse 9 to
12 so the Bible says here receiving the
end of your faith even the salvation of
your souls of which salvation the
prophets have inquired and searched
diligently who prophesy of the grace
that should come unto you searching what
or what matter of time the spirit of
Christ which was in them did signify
when it testified beforehand the
sufferings of Christ and the glory that
should be the glory that should
follow unto whom it was revealed that
not unto themselves but unto us they did
Minister the things which are now
reported unto you by them that they have
preached the gospel unto you with the
Holy Ghost sent down from heaven which
things Angels
what all right so what do angels desire
to look
into what do they desire to look
into the the gospel right the The
Mystery of the Gospel okay because they
desire to look into these things because
H they are a mystery may I ask you a
question who do you think was the first
angel that desired to look
into this
secret yeah
yeah remember we we just read that
Lucifer was jealous because he could not
know the secrets of God's purposes are
you with me all right so so HH we're
going to see something so amazing so
beautiful
about the Gospel of Jesus Christ listen
another statement from the from the
great controversy page 495 listen to
this in all the councils of God Christ
was a participant while Lucifer was not
permitted thus to enter into the Divine
purposes why question this Mighty Angel
should Christ have a Supremacy why is he
thus honored above Lucifer so who did
Lucifer want to be like he wanted to be
like Christ and and and as he looked at
this honor that that that Christ had he
wanted that honor
himself yeah he wanted that Glory
himself in fact the Bible tells us in
Isaiah 14: 12-4 that Luke Lucifer said I
will be
like like who all right so I got a
question for you who did Lucifer want to
be
like Jesus so who is
Jesus yeah who let's do that who did he
want to be like like Jesus Isaiah 14
says he wanted to be like the most high
he wanted the
glory of Jesus
Christ but God said
what
no no you
can't and the question is why not why
couldn't Lucifer have the glory of
Christ all right all right well because
what because he's a created being amen
but but check this out the
the yeah okay all right so so Le let's
look at some other things here and uh
we're we're still Gathering Together our
pieces to put this puzzle together so
let's go to 1 Corinthians chapter 2
because we want to discover uh the we're
talking about the parable of Proverbs 8
but we want to discover something we
want to discover what this mystery is
what this secret was that was from the
foundations of the earth so 1
Corinthians chapter
2 1
Corinthians chapter 2
with verse six when you're there please
say Amen the Bible says how be it we
speak wisdom among them that are perfect
yet not the wisdom of this world nor of
the princes of this world that come to
not but we speak the wisdom of who in a
what even the what hidden wisdom which
God what ordained when before the world
unto our Glory so this
wisdom was ordained
when be now how many of you remember
when we read Proverbs 8 and it was
talking about how wisdom was around
before what the foundations of the Earth
right hey when we compare that with
First Corinthians we're seeing that the
Bible is telling us here that this
mystery of God this hidden wisdom or
secret was ordained before the
foundation of the world which verse
verse eight which none of the princes of
this world knew for had they known it
they would not have crucified who the
Lord Of Glory so had they known what
this wisdom was they would not have
crucified Christ Jesus so what we see is
that this wisdom was before the world
let's go over to the the book of
Ephesians chapter 1 Ephesians chapter
1 verse five what is this
mystery that was before the world was
even created Ephesians 1:5 the Bible
says
here having predestined unto us the
adoption of children by Jesus Christ to
himself according to the good pleasure
of his will stop right there for a
second what does it mean to
predestin yeah what does it mean that
that God uh predestined
us is God saying here that I saved you
against your
will is that what he's saying no what's
he
saying so so basically you know like um
like I could you know yeah many of us
like predestin our children for what we
want them to be yeah I want my son or my
daughter to be a doctor it's it's God
it's it's our will for our children but
do they have freedom of choice to reject
what we want for them yeah so God in
other words the Bible is saying telling
us that before everything was God had
predetermined that he wanted us saved
that he wanted us in heaven with him
amen so so that's what we're reading
here and this happened before the
creation of the world so uh verse six to
to the praise of the glory of his grace
wherein he has made us accepted in the
Beloved in whom we have Redemption
through his blood the Forgiveness of
sins according to the riches of his
grace wherein he has abounded toward us
in all wisdom and Prudence having made
known unto us the mystery of his
will according to the good pleasure
which he himself has purposed in
himself that in the dispensation of the
fullness of time he might gather
together in all things in Christ both
which are in heaven and which are on
earth even in him in whom also we have
obtained an inheritance being
predestined according to the purpose of
him who worketh all things after the
counsel of his will so what we're
clearly seeing here is that God before
you were
created with all your messed up
stuff with all the Rebellion that with
everything God
predestined you to be in heaven with
him he saying pastor why would that be a
secret what hold on remember this is a
mystery it's a mystery from when from
before the foundations of the earth we
we understand that Lucifer wanted to
look into the hidden things of God but
was not permitted to and the question is
why but we're going to go on let's go
over to Romans chapter 8 Romans chapter
8 Romans the e8th chapter and we're
going to pick up on this on this thre
said want you to notice Romans 8: 28
to30 if it's on the screen let's just
read it Romans 8 is it up there Romans
8:28 to 30 it says this and we know that
all things work together for the good of
them that love God to them that are
called according to his what purpose
verse 29 for whom he did for know he
also did what predestined I got a
question for you when did God predestin
us was there a time that he did not
predestined
us was there a time no no no no so so as
old as God is is as old as he had you in
his
mind
wow with all your messed up
stuff now now please note God did not
predestin you to mess up are you with me
he predestined you to be saved but he
knew because God is all what all knowing
and yet he predes destinated us to be
what conformed to the image of his who
that he might be the firstborn among
many Brethren now that term is
interesting because firstborn it means
begotten that he might
be something to
come did you catch that just now he
might be the firstborn among
who so who are the
Brethren who are the Brethren yeah it
will be Humanity right so the Bible's
telling us that God sometime in the past
predestined us to be conformed to
someone else who would become one of
us is that right all right very good
verse 30 verse 30 verse 30 says moreover
whom he did what predestinate them he
also called and whom he called them he
also what Justified and whom he
justified them he also glorified very
good so now we're on the same page we're
understanding what God is saying here
and and the Mystery then the mystery is
that Christ would come in the flesh to
become one of us in fact we don't need
to guess 1 Timothy chter 3 verse 16
let's see what that verse says
yes I'm
waiting 1 Timothy chapter three verse
16 I'll go to my
Bible verse 16 is it up there check this
out and without what so what does that
mean without
controversy is there any
challenge without okay without
controversy what god without controversy
see
great is the what is the what everyone
mystery huh mystery there's no greater
mystery there is no greater secret great
is the mystery of godliness what is the
mystery of godliness what is the mystery
that was held from the found what is the
history that was put in place before the
the mystery that was put in place before
the world was even created God was what
manifest In the Flesh justified in the
spirit seen of angels preached unto the
Gentiles believed on in the world
received up into Glory the greatest
mystery of all
existence is when Jesus became
incarnate
so Lucifer wanted to know what the
secret was
yeah why is he the Son of
God why does he have such honor why why
is why does the father HH uh look at him
with such uh uh you know why is he so
highly honored he did not know
something are you catching this there's
something he did not know not only is
there something he did not know there's
something else he did not know which is
that he was the center of the thing that
he did not know y'all not catching me
man but but listen God could not tell
him that he was the center of what he
did not know because then it would look
like God was predestined pre you know
word he had predestinated him to
fall no no no no no no no no we're not
going to say anything because if I were
to say something then it would appear oh
god well you predestined this and then
this is really your
fault no God had four knowledge but what
he says is listen uh this this cannot
appear in any way shape or form that I
we are responsible for sin so even
though we know what's coming it's going
to be a
secret it's going to be a
secret so so so check this out with with
that understanding in mind right by the
way you know know so the Bible tells us
that God calls the things that be not as
though they what as though they
were so so with this understanding in
mind now let's go back to Proverbs 8 and
check out the amazing message found in
Proverbs 8 let's go back Proverbs
chapter
8 and again I want you to notice a few
things here now we're not going to read
through all those vers again I'm just
going to show you some key verses okay
first verse we're going to go to is
verse
23 Proverbs chapter 8 verse 23 so again
the question is is Proverbs 8 showing
that Christ was born sometime in the
past that he was brought forth he has a
point of origin or is Proverbs 8 telling
us is the parable of Proverbs 8 telling
us something else so check this out
chapter 8 verse 23 we're going to look
at three verses in Proverbs 8 verse 2 3
so verse
23 verse 23 it
reads Uh I that is wisdom was set up
from Everlasting from the beginning or
the Earth ever was all right so I was
what everyone I was what wisdom was what
set up set up that word setup is the
Hebrew nasak and here's what it means it
means to pour out so if I to ask you
what is wisdom saying here
here another word for another way we
could translate I was set up would be I
was what poured out now you want to hear
something interesting so wisdom right
which we understand is the mystery of
the gospel God manifest In the Flesh was
set up or poured out God Jesus speaking
as wisdom personified says I was poured
out before the foundation of the
world you know what the term poured out
means it is used 15 times that Hebrew
that word nasak is used 15 times in the
Old
Testament to mean a drink
offering now what do the offerings point
to all the offerings in the Bible what
do they point to they point to the what
they point to the sacrifice of who Jesus
Christ Isaiah 54 let's go to Isaiah 54
hold your place here we're just going to
do it on the screen so you stay where
you are let's put up Isaiah
54 and verse Isaiah 53 and verse 12 on
the screen the word literally means to
pour out as an offering I got a question
for you did Jesus pour His Life out as
an
offering in
heaven did
he no where did he pour His Life out as
an offering on the earth Isaiah 53:12
I want you to notice what the Bible says
here Isaiah 53:12 therefore will I
divide with him a portion uh with the
great he shall divide the spoil with his
with the strong because he has what
poured out his soul unto what so check
this
out what was set up before the creation
of the world was it Jesus coming into
existence what was
it the fact that he would come to this
world to die on a cross for our
sins what year was that by the
way tell me tell me you know what year
did he die 31 ad keep that year in mind
all right so we see whoa the Bible is
telling us here this Parable is telling
us that wisdom The Plan of Salvation the
gospel story God manifest In the Flesh
that was set up before the world ever
was that was set up before anything else
happened that what has been in existence
as long as God has been in
existence okay the word nasak also means
anointed
so I have a question for
you when was Jesus
anointed 20 what
ad you got 27 ad and 31 ad are those two
dates prophetic dates Ione to know if
those two yeah what prophecy do those
two dates belong
to yeah Daniel 9 the 70 week
prophecy which prophesied the
coming the going
forth of the
Messiah okay wait who in the world would
have thought that Proverbs chapter
8 would be telling
us that before anything ever
existed God loved
you with all your messed up
craziness with all your foolishness with
all your ups and downs before anything
before before anything was created God
said God the father and the son said all
right this is what we're going to do the
the plan is
this and it's going to be
our
secret can't tell
anyone the secret will be held within
the godhead we know what's going on and
and and and when Lucifer begins to make
his move not because we predestined it
but when he begins to make his move
that's when we're going to begin to
start to make it
known that the Son of
God the the the one who will come to the
one who receive Glory and Honor because
of what he is going to do in the
future do you know Lucifer wanted to be
like Jesus
Lucifer you can't be like Jesus you
can't be like the son you want to know
why because if you took his place when
you got to the Cross you would reject
it and everybody would be lost nah you
can't uhuh no you're not gonna and by
the way if you knew what the son was
going to do you would not be wanting his
glory
so so so far we see Proverbs 8 is
speaking to us about F it's a parable
speaking to us about future events but
declaring those things as though they
were before anything ever
existed one more word I want to share
with
you uh it by the way uh notice with me
very quickly if you will the book of uh
Psalms Psalm chapter 2 let's turn there
quickly Psalm chapter
2 so so remember we read in Proverbs I
was uh I was set up um before anything
was brought forth so that word nasak one
more time Psalm chapter
2 Psalm chapter 2 and uh verse one we'll
start with verse one when you're there
say Amen the Bible says why do the
Heathen rage rage and the people imagine
a vain thing the kings of the earth set
themselves and the rulers take counsel
against the Lord and against his
anointed saying let us break their bands
of and Cast Away their CTS so let us
break their bands aund whose bands
aunder the Lord and his what and his
anointed let us separate
them did this happen on the
earth yeah did the Pharisees and
Sadducees and the Jewish Nations seek to
separate the father from the from his
anointed yeah so Psalm 2 is a reference
to Christ
incarnate amen are are you with me now
right now let's read on uh uh uh verse
verse four he he that sth in the heavens
shall laugh and the Lord shall have them
in derision then shall he speak unto
them in his wrath and vets them in his
sore spirit yet have I set my king upon
my Holy Hill
all right so I what is he going to do
set his what king upon his Holy Hill and
then I will declare the decree the Lord
has said unto me thou art my son this
day have I begotten
thee did did the Heathen rage Around
Jesus did they think that they had him
beat
did Christ did God resurrect his son did
he resurrect his son yeah did he bring
his son to Heaven did he set him on his
Holy Hill in heaven yeah so I got a
question for you when the Bible says in
revelation: 15 that Jesus Christ is the
first begotten of the
dead of the Dead what does that
signify that when he resurrected from
the grave
he became the first begotten of the
Dead in Psalm 24 there's a celebration
being described where all the angels are
worshiping the king of glory who is
coming into his
kingdom Hebrews chapter 1 picks up on
that same worship and says it was that
day that God said this is my son let all
the Angels do what worship him so check
this out psalm chapter 8 is not only
telling us about Jesus coming as a man
it is not only telling us about him
dying the death on the cross it is also
telling us that he would be set up in
heaven as God's first begotten of the
Dead meaning Psalm 8 is pointing
us to the events of the Life Death
burial resurrection and Ascension of
Jesus Christ
there's one
more that same chapter Proverbs 8 the
Bible says that before anything was I
was brought
forth now that's the key one I want to
focus on I was brought forth and some
people say there it is that word brought
brought forth actually means
begotten so this is telling us that
Jesus was what
begotten back in eternity he has a
beginning
point but listen to me if everything
else in this chapter is telling us is
pointing to things that Christ had not
yet done but would do in his Incarnation
then that verse talking about Christ
being brought forth or being begotten
what is that telling us it is pointing
us to the fact that Jesus Christ would
come to this earth in the form of a man
to become the only begotten of
God the prophecy the parable of Proverbs
8 is an
unfolding of the
prophecy called the 70
weeks I will get excited by myself all
alone it is pointing forward to the in
in Carnation of Jesus Christ and telling
us that that Incarnation the plan was
all set in place was all laid in place
way before anything else not that Jesus
was set in place not that Jesus was
brought forth but the
plan to redeem us with all our messed
upness with all our craziness God looked
down into the future and said
look I
predestined I want we are going to do
everything in our power
to redeem and to save
mankind you know what's beautiful about
this check this out let's go back up we
just have a few more thoughts and then
we'll close up so Proverbs chapter 8
notice Proverbs 8 I'm going to go back
up to verse one in context of everything
we've just heard I want you to check
this out Proverbs chapter 8 okay
Proverbs 8 and look at verse one when
you there say
Amen does not wisdom cry and
understanding put forth her voice
she standeth in the top of high places
by the way in the places of the path she
cries at the gates at the entry of the
city at the coming in at the doors okay
that's the first three verses and then
jump down with me to verse 36 or verse
32 now therefore hearken unto me oh ye
children for blessed are they that keep
my my ways hear instruction and be wise
and refuse it not blessed is the man
that heareth me and WTH daily at my
Gates waiting at the post of my door for
who so findeth me findeth life and shall
obtain favor of the Lord but he that
sinth against me wrongs his own soul and
all they that hate me love
death let me ask you a question did
Jesus as wisdom ever lift up his voice
in the
streets did he yeah that's his whole
mission when he came to this earth
wisdom began preaching in the streets
amen so check this out then the whole
context of Proverbs chapter eight is
wisdom coming in the
flesh and preaching to Israel to
humanity and letting them know Hey
listen the father sent me before the
world was created I
am before every before Abraham was I am
I am the self existent one the one that
has life underived unborrowed and I am
here because there was a plan that was
that goes back into the ages of Eternity
Before Time began to save you and had
they known this wisdom they would not
have
crucified the king of
glory in fact Proverbs
8 is a replica of Proverbs 1 and I want
you to turn there I promise you we're
getting ready to close
I
promise Proverbs 1 Proverbs 1 and I want
you to notice verse 20 when you're there
say Amen wisdom crith without she utth
her voice in the streets did we just
read that in Proverbs 8 yeah so would we
would it be safe for us to say hey
Proverbs 1 is talking about the same
thing as Proverbs 8 check this out so
wisdom that is Christ crying in the
streets uh uh verse 21 she cth in the
chief places of The Concourse and the
opening of the gates and in the city she
utth her words saying how long you
simple ones will you love Simplicity did
Jesus have to basically say this to the
Jews yeah yeah let's read on uh verse
verse 23 turn you at my
reprove behold I will pour out my spirit
on you and I will make know my words
unto you but I have called and you
refuse
I stretched out my
hands stretched out my hands
and no man regarded yeah yeah so this is
this is wisdom being personified or or
personified as Christ but you have set
at not all my counsels did the Jews do
that did they do that did they set at
not all his counsels yeah H I will also
because you have set not all my counsels
and with none of my reproof I will also
laugh at your
Calamity I will mock when your fear
comes when your fear comes as a
desolation and your destruction cometh
as a whirlwind let me ask you something
did God tell us in the 70 week prophecy
that those who rejected the Messiah the
coming anointed one that they would end
up being
destroyed Proverbs chapter 8 Proverbs
chapter 8 is a parable of the coming of
Christ why could Satan
not take the place of the
Messiah listen
what did he want the glory that Jesus
had yeah do you know that when Jesus was
on the earth and he was about to go to
the Cross do you remember he said father
glorify me now with the glory that we
had before the world
began what was that
Glory it was the
cross Satan you really want this
Glory are you willing to go and
sacrifice yourself no n saying you can't
have the glory of the Son of God because
the glory of the Son of God is that he
would come and die for a world that was
lying in
sin the glory of the Son of God was that
he would willingly lay down his life
that you and I as Sinners would be saved
Lucifer are you ready to do
that
now and by the way you're a created
being and a created being cannot do
what the Sun is going to do because the
sun is not
created the sun has no
beginning let me say this way from the
very beginning of time Jesus has always
been the Lamb of God there was never a
time that he was not the Lamb of God
even though the Lamb of God was not
slain until the cross he had always been
the Lamb of God he had always been the
begotten son he had always been the
redeemed the Savior and this is what
Satan could not understand huh what Son
of God but uh Christ
what
Ephesians our closing verse Ephesians
chapter 1 verse4 I'm going to ask hi me
if you prepare to come forward to pray
Ephesians chapter
1 verse 4 can we get that up on the on
the
screen the Bible says according as he
has chosen Us in him when everyone when
before the foundation of the world isn't
that
beautiful he chose you not when the
world was founded he chose you before
the foundation of the world you were in
the heart of God you were in the heart
of the Son of God you were in the heart
of the Messi
mesiah before you were ever before this
world was ever created you know what
that says to me man Lord you looked down
and saw all the
craziness that we would go through and
you said we are still going to make an
attempt to redeem them God has dreams
for
us God has he is his desire is the
desire of
ages it is a desire that was not birth
or was not did not come up at some point
in time it has been throughout all ages
it is the
desire of all
ages God desires you with an everlasting
love and beloved this is why as we look
at the cross the cross tells us that
this is not something that Jesus
became the cross reveals to us that this
is who God has always
been that's why throughout all eternity
we will be studying the SS of Salvation
we will be studying the cross why
because within the cross is the mystery
and the fullness of all the glory of God
I'm going to invite you guys to please
kneel dear heavenly father how marvelous
and wonderful you
are father
we thank you for
everything and for sending your son to
die on the cross for
us Lord we have nothing nothing to repay
you
with not even our lives can pay for what
you've done for us
but Lord we thank you for the wonderful
gift you gave to us and we accept
it we accept that wonderful gift that
was your son Jesus
Christ Lord we thank you for the message
you have given to Pastor I Myers to give
to
us Lord we ask you that you may Keep On
Blessing
him that you may never leave
him that you may keep him that you may
keep using him so others may know about
you thank you
Lord Lord we thank you for everything
not because we deserve it
we thank and we praise for the blood you
shed on that
cross Lord that blood that doesn't stain
but
cleans Lord we thank you for
that for
Jesus in His holy name amen
amen for